# **Christopher James Shepherd**

26 Eider Apartments, 73 Perryfield Way, London NW9 7FD



chris\_shepherd2@hotmail.com +447929 672636 www.chrisshepherd.io www.github.com/cshep4/

Full clean driving licence - Car owner

### **Profile**

Highly motivated and skilled Software Engineer with over four years' experience having worked in various Agile teams, developing large scale distributed systems for multiple big-name companies. Having successfully shipped a number of big projects, I am proficient in several programming languages including Java, Go, Kotlin, PHP and JavaScript, as well as having knowledge of various DevOps tools. I have also released two mobile apps to both the Google Play Store and Apple App Store in my spare time with a total user count of over 12,000.

### **Experience**

# <u>January 2019-Present – Curve, Software Engineer:</u>

Curve is a Fin-Tech startup based in London. It's aim is to build a platform which will simplify people's financial life by connecting their accounts to one smart debit card. Curve has recently secured \$55m in Series B funding and another £6m in crowdfunding, whilst also being named the UK's 10<sup>th</sup> hottest startup by LinkedIn.

- Working as part of a small agile team designing, developing and maintaining highly-available, scalable and robust distributed systems.
- Successfully shipped multiple projects from design phase to production including Curve Cash, Contact Discovery and Curve Send.
- Writing microservices in Go which communicate in various ways such as gRPC, REST, GraphQL and RabbitMQ. Hosted on Kubernetes with Istio.
- I also spend time working on our legacy systems written in PHP, whilst contributing to the current move away from monolithic architecture to microservices.
- Part of the on-call rota to help ensure all services are available and running correctly at all times.

#### October 2015-January 2019 – IBM, Developer:

- Worked on projects for a number of large external clients mainly as a back-end developer. Writing server-side code in both microservice and monolithic architectures using Java 8 and Spring Boot, with tools such Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL and Redis.
- Using various software development techniques such as Test Driven Development and a number of Agile methodologies.
- I also spent some time on a project as a full stack developer writing in Java, using Spring Boot with Gradle and AngularJS to create a mobile app. The project also used TDD and pair programming.
- Responsibilities for each project have included developing user stories, fixing defects and code reviewing.
- Carried out a short cognitive side project for a PoC. I created a back-end using Node.js and Express to link a mobile app with IBM's Watson Conversation web service and a Cloudant NoSQL database.
- I undertook several training courses, both technical and non-technical, including MEAN Stack, Core Java, Java Spring and an Agile DevOps Workshop.
- I was part of the Blockchain Practice Area, this involves carrying out training and gaining the IBM Blockchain Essentials for Developers certification.
- I also passed the Oracle Certified Java Associate certification during my time at the company.

### May 2012-September 2012; June 2013-August 2014 – Motor Design Ltd, Software Developer:

Motor Design Ltd is a company that produces Motor-CAD, a thermal analysis software package for electric motors and generators. I carried out an industrial placement year as part of my degree and was subsequently nominated by them for the Placement Student of the Year award.

- Learned and utilised advanced skills programming in Object Pascal using Delphi XE2, creating various features for a software package by interpreting physics and mathematical equations.
- Created conductor placement and magnetic winding design tools for Motor-CAD.
- Produced an interactive editor for solver circuit design also for Motor-CAD.
- Implemented functionality for Motor-CAD to check for updates using a PHP script I created on the company website.
- Greatly developed my analytical skills and programming ability, as well as encouraging working using my own initiative.

# **Education**

<u>De Montfort University, Leicester – First Class (4.0 GPA equivalent) BSc Hons, Computer Games</u> Programming:

2014-2015 – Third year modules: Games Programming

Mobile Games Development

Secure Web Application Development

Fuzzy Logic and Knowledge Based Systems (AI)
Final Year Project (Social media web application)

2012-2013 – Second year modules: C++ for Games Programmers

Artificial Intelligence and Modelling for Games

Introduction to Graphics and Interactive 3D Modelling

**Database Design and Implementation** 

2011-2012 – First year modules: C++ Programming

Games Architecture, Design and Development

**Creative Client Computing** 

**Computer Systems** 

Shrewsbury Sixth Form College, Shrewsbury - A-Levels: Computing, Mathematics, Physics:

Lakelands School, Sports and Languages College - 9 GCSEs grade A-C

### Personal Projects

- 1. A gym tracking application where users can log in, store their performance in the gym and view progress with various analytics. Written in HTML/CSS, PHP, MySQL and JavaScript with some APIs rewritten in Kotlin using Spring Boot. This is written with an MVC architecture. The website is hosted using Heroku and the MySQL database is hosted using AWS Relational Database Service. The website URL is www.gyme.co.uk.
- 2. A World Cup 2018 Predictor app in the Ionic Framework, with back-end APIs written in Kotlin using Spring Boot. The intention of the app is for users to compete against friends by predicting football scores for the 2018 World Cup. Up to date fixtures and results are fetched from an external API. The back-end of the app was written entirely using TDD and is hosted on Heroku. The app uses adverts to generate revenue provided by Google's Admob service. The app was released to the Apple App Store and Google Play Store. I decided to take this app down from the app stores once the World Cup finished though, with a final user count of 6812.
- 3. A Premier League Predictor app extended from the World Cup Predictor. This is also used to compete against friends by predicting scores for the 18/19 Premier League. This app contains a lot of new features, such as live match scores and commentary. The back-end is now written as polyglot microservices and hosted using Kubernetes. This is currently available on the Apple App Store. The app uses adverts to generate revenue provided by Google's Admob service.
- 4. A portfolio website built in Angular 6, with a small serverless back-end written in Go. The front-end is hosted on Firebase and the back-end on AWS Lambda. This can be found at <a href="www.chrisshepherd.io">www.chrisshepherd.io</a>, along with more details about my other projects.